Shawn Smith

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/shawnsmith11/

GitHub: github.com/srsmitho
Portfolio: www.shawnsmith.work

2550 S Main St #6306 South Salt Lake, UT 84115 **(402) 616-7639**

srsmith11@live.com

SUMMARY

Performance driven and motivated junior full stack developer with a diverse skill set. Comfortable with modern JavaScript technologies and has a passion for creating products that are meant to be shared. Superb communication and strategic planning skills from 4 years of brewery leadership roles.

EDUCATION

University of Utah/Devpoint Labs — Full-Stack Web Development Certificate - May 2020 - July 2020

University of Nebraska-Lincoln — B.S. in Fisheries and Wildlife (Wildlife Biology) - August 2007 - May 2012

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Strap Tank Brewery, Springville/Lehi, UT *Head Brewer* 2018-2020

- Managed scheduling, inventory, and implemented ERP software for two locations
- Created Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) for all processes
- Responsible for all recipe formulation
- Improved bottling yields and packaged quality standards
- Created and led beer education courses for servers

Uinta Brewing Company, Salt Lake City, UT *QA and RD Manager* 2017–2018

- Developed over 10 new products to be distributed nationwide
- Created weekly KPI reports to improve processes
- Managed a team of three and responsible for hiring
- Created laboratory SOPs and training logs
- Collaborated with multiple departments to implement food safety plan

Brewing Supervisor 2016-2017

- Led the brewing department for seven months until a Brewmaster was hired
- Created SOPs for a 4030 gallon brewhouse
- Managed a team of eight and responsible for hiring
- Responsible for \$500,000+ of product in fermentations

SKILLS

JavaScript

React.js

HTML

CSS

Rails

SOL

Git/GitHub

PROJECTS

Live, Laugh, Lager Allows users to review beers, create posts, and find breweries with a third party API. Made with React.js and Rails.

Family Talk
Group project that is similar to Pintrest.
Allows users to create boards, posts within the boards, ability to like and comment on posts, and the option to follow boards. Made with React.js and Rails.

DnD Characters
Hackathon 2 project
that stores a user's
Dungeons and Dragons
character and
equipment. I
completed all backend
work. Made with
React.js and Rails.